Guide to the South and Southeast Asian Broadside Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
South and Southeast Asian broadside collection
1810-1910
MS 2003
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(3 boxes)
This collection primarily consists of late nineteenth to early twentieth century newspaper broadsides focused on Siam and Dutch, British, and French colonial empires in South and Southeast Asia. Sources for the broadsides are primarily The Illustrated London News, Le Petit Parisien, and Le Petit Journal. Recurring topics include the European travels of Siam's King Chulalongkorn and his diplomats, various wars in the regions - the French-Indochina wars, Selangor Civil War, Perak War, Achenese War, Anglo-Afghan wars – and depictions of sociocultural and ecological life throughout South and Southeast Asia. The collection also includes a series of early twentieth century journal articles on Annam, Borneo, Burma, Indochina, Malaya, New Guinea, Siam, and Singapore.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily consists of late nineteenth to early twentieth century newspaper broadsides focused on Siam and Dutch, British, and French colonial empires in South and Southeast Asia. Sources for the broadsides are primarily The Illustrated London News, Le Petit Parisien, and Le Petit Journal. Recurring topics include the European travels of Siam's King Chulalongkorn and his diplomats, various wars in the regions - the French-Indochina wars, Selangor Civil War, Perak War, Achenese War, Anglo-Afghan wars – and depictions of sociocultural and ecological life throughout South and Southeast Asia. The collection also includes a series of early twentieth century journal articles on Annam, Borneo, Burma, Indochina, Malaya, New Guinea, Siam, and Singapore.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Southeast Asia Collection Curator, 2014.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged according to country.
Afghanistan; Borneo; Burma; China; France -- Colonies -- Asia; Great Britain -- Colonies -- Asia; Indochina; Indonesia; Netherlands -- Colonies -- Asia; New Guinea; Philippines; Thailand; Broadsides (notices)
- Early twentieth century journal articles (Malaya, New Guinea, Borneo, Indo-Early twentieth-century journal articles (Malaya, New Guinea, Borneo, Indo-China, Annam, Singapore, Burma, Siam, China, Annam, Singapore, Burma, Siam), Circa 1800s-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Supplement to The Sphere (Singapore), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Illustrated London News illustrations and articles (Burma, Afghanistan, Siam, Indochina, Malaya), 1852-1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Engravings, illustrations, photographs, newspaper articles (Borneo), 1850s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Liebig trading cards, 1800s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Engravings and newspaper articles (Burma), 1810-1895 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspaper articles and illustrations on The Achinese War (Indonesia), 1873-1904 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Le Petit Parisien articles and illustrations (India, Siam), 1893-1907 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Le Petit Journal illustrations (India, Siam, Cambodia), 1893-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Journal Des Voyages illustrations (Siam), 1893, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Engravings depicting eighteenth century Siam, 1800s-1900s (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newspaper articles on Visit of Siamese King to London (Siam), 1897 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- L' Illustre Soleil du Dimanche articles on the King of Siam's visit to France (Siam), 1897 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Engravings, newspaper illustrations and articles on eighteenth and nineteenth century Tonkin, Annam, Cochin China, 1800s-1900s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Victoriae Reginae Legal Documents (Malaya, Singapore), 1866 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Illustrations, and articles on late nineteenth and early twentieth century Siam, 1800s-1900s (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newspaper articles and illustrations on the Second Anglo-Afghan War, 1878-1879 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspaper articles and illustrations on the French-Indochina Wars, 1858-1883 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Engravings, newspaper articles, and illustrations on nineteenth and twentieth century Philippines, 1800s-1900s (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Illustration and article on Arfak Village, Memiwa, New Guinea, by Professor Friedrich Ratzel, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 4)